黔东南州，二零二零年
初中毕业升学统一考试
英语听力材料朗读，现在开始。
第一节。
听句子两遍，选择正确的应答语，完成一至五小题，并用2
铅笔把答题卡上对应题目的答案标号涂黑。
1. Would you like some orange juice?
2. How can I get to No.1 middle school?
3. Tom, don't run in the classroom.
It's dangerous. 4.
this is Amy speaking.
5. What's the weather like today?
五，
6. What's the weather like today?
第二节，听对话两遍，选择语。
对话内容相符的图画，其中有一幅是多余的。完成六至十小题，并用2
铅笔把答题卡上对应题目的答案标号涂黑。
What's the weather like
What's the weather like today?
9. What's the weather like today?
Well, it means smoking is not allowed here.
It's fine today.
Let's play soccer together.
That sounds good.
It's fine today.
Let's play soccer together.
That sounds good.
9. What time do you get up every morning?
I often get up at a quarter to six.
What time do get up every morning?
10. Shall we go to the zoo this weekend?
That's a good idea.
I like monkeys best.
Shall we go to the this weekend?
That's a good idea.
I like monkeys best.
第三节，听对。
对话和问题两遍，根据对话内容选择最佳答案，完成十一至十五小题，并
用二
铅笔把答题卡上对应题目的答案标号涂黑。
What would you like for breakfast, David?
I'd like some bread and milk.
12. would David like for breakfast?
12. Tony, what about riding a to the park tomorrow?
Oh no, my bike is broken.
Then let's take a bus.
Okay, I will wait for you at the bus stop.
Question. How will they go to the park tomorrow?
13. Lucy, the blue skirt looks so beautiful on you.
13. 13. the skirt beautiful beautiful you.
14. you. My mom bought it for me.
Question. What color is Lucy's skirt?
Lucy, the blue skirt looks so beautiful on you.
Thank you. My mom bought it for me.
Question. What color is Lucy's skirt?
14. Dale, would you like to go to the with me?
Sorry, I can't.
I fell off my bike and hurt my right leg.
I'm sorry to hear that.
You should have a rest.
Question. Why can't go to the library with a girl?
Dale, would you like to go to the library with me?
Sorry, I can't.
I fell off my bike and hurt my right leg.
I'm sorry to hear that.
You should have a rest.
Question. Why can't Dale go to the library with a girl?
15. Peter, what kind of music do you like?
Rock music or pop music?
Neither. I like live music because it can make me relaxed.
Question. What kind of music does Peter like?
Peter, what kind of music do you like?
Rock music or pop music?
Neither. I like live music because it can make me relaxed.
Question. What kind of music does Peter like?
第四节，听短文三遍，根据所听内容，在表格里的横线处填入适当的单词
，每处现填一词。
of music? What kind
Example 1. A mother is looking at her smartphone while her little son is in danger
in the river.
Example 2. At a family party, the children as well as their parents have their eyes
fixed on smartphone screens, leaving their grandparents alone.
The two examples show that the overuse of smartphones can lead to bad results.
By overusing them, you may pay no attention to others' safety.
Besides, overusing them does harm to the relationships between you and your friends
and family. So, you should use smartphones in the right way.
Use them less and focus more on the people around.
Smartphones have made our lives more convenient.
However, they can also bring some problems.
Here are two examples.
Example 1. A mother is looking at her smartphone while her little son is in danger
in the river.
Example 2. At a family party, the children as well as their parents have their eyes
fixed on smartphone screens, leaving their grandparents alone.
The two examples show that the overuse of smartphones can lead to bad results.
By overusing them, you may pay no attention to others' safety.
Besides, overusing them does harm to the relationships between you and your friends
and family. So, you should use smartphones in the right way.
them less and focus more on the people around.
Smartphones have made our lives more convenient.
However, they can also bring some problems.
Here are two examples.
Example 1. A mother is looking at her smartphone while her little son is in danger
in the river.
Example 2. At a family party, the children as well as their parents have their eyes
fixed on smartphone screens, leaving their grandparents alone.
The two examples show that the overuse of smartphones can lead to bad results.
By overusing them, you may pay no attention to others' safety.
Besides, overusing them does harm to the relationships between you and your friends
and family. So, you should use smartphones in the right way.
Use them less and focus more on the people around.
听力材料朗读完毕。